http://www.cdnhemochromatosis.ca/privacy/

Home » Privacy Policy
Privacy Policy
We Respect Your Privacy
At the Canadian Hemochromatosis Society (“CHS,” or “the Society), we respect your privacy. We never sell, trade or loan your information to any other organization and we ensure that CHS meets privacy principles and requirements with respect to personal information under applicable Canadian privacy legislation. The purpose of this privacy statement is to inform our supporters, volunteers, and other individuals we deal with (“you,” or “your”) about how we collect, use, disclose and protect personal information in our custody or control.
Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your Personal Information
Personal information is information about an identifiable individual, as more particularly described under applicable privacy legislation. Employees of CHS, volunteers and other representatives collect, use and disclose personal information in a number of circumstances in the course of the Society’s day-to-day activities. Depending on the circumstances, CHS may ask you to provide your personal contact information (including your address, telephone number or e-mail address), your credit card or other financial information or information about your opinions or preferences with respect to participation in events, programs or services offered by the Society and to share your personal experiences with hemochromatosis.
CHS will then use or disclose the personal information it collects from you to, as applicable, manage its relationship with you, process donations; administer programs that benefit hemochromatosis patients and their families; and inform all individuals associated with CHS (employees, volunteers and other interested parties) about the Society’s events, funding needs and opportunities to volunteer or donate or otherwise participate in the work of the Society. If you choose to share your personal experiences with hemochromatosis, CHS will also use that information to conduct research and statistical analysis designed to help CHS understand how hemochromatosis impacts Canadians so that we can credibly engage the medical community; members of government; charitable foundations and the media to reduce and eventually eliminate the ways hemochromatosis impacts all our lives.
In addition to the above, personal information may be disclosed as required to meet legal, contractual, regulatory, insurance, audit and security requirements, or as otherwise permitted or required by law. Where applicable, the Society may transfer your personal information to third party service providers hired to assume certain administrative responsibilities or provide certain services on our behalf. Some of these service providers may be located outside of Canada, including in the United States, and your personal information may be collected, used, disclosed, stored and processed in the United States or elsewhere outside of Canada for the purposes described in this privacy statement. We require these service providers to use your personal information only to perform the services we have retained them to provide and we take reasonable steps to ensure that these service providers comply with legal requirements under privacy legislation in Canada.
Currently, the Society maintains its database on a secure system located in the United States of America. This service provider offers state-of-the-art security for all data in the Society’s custody or control and is a cost-effective way for the Society to manage its data.
The Society has taken reasonable measures to ensure that personal information handled by its service providers on our behalf is protected and not used or disclosed for purposes other than as directed by the Society, subject only to local legal requirements applicable to those service providers.
Our Website
The only personal information which we collect about you when you use our website is what you tell us about yourself, for example, by completing an online form or information you provide to us through the “Contact Us” section, when you send us an e-mail or when you use the forum.
As most websites do, however, our website tracks usage patterns on an anonymous basis. Your identity cannot reasonably be ascertained from this information. Each time you visit our website, our server records your Internet Service Provider, the date and time of your visit, the pages you visit and the documents downloaded, the searches you performed, and the referring URLs you came from. We use this non-personal information to optimize our website service.
For your convenience, we may offer links from our website to other websites. However, the Society is not responsible for, nor do we accept any liability for, the personal information collection, use and disclosure practices of other entities to which our website may link. You should consult the privacy policies of these other entities before providing any personal information on their websites.
Your Consent
CHS collects, uses and discloses your personal information with your consent, except as permitted or required by law. Generally, by providing us with your personal information, we will assume that you consent to our collection, use and disclosure of such information for the purposes identified or described in this privacy statement, if applicable, or otherwise communicated to you at the time of collection. Subject to contractual and legal restrictions, you may withdraw your consent to our collection, use and disclosure of personal information at any time but, if you do withdraw your consent, we may no longer be able to provide certain of our services or programs to you.
Security
We protect your personal information using physical, electronic or procedural security measures appropriate to the sensitivity of the information in our custody or control, which may include safeguards to protect against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use or modification.
Access, Correction and Contacting Us
If you wish to request access to or correction of your personal information or you wish to inquire about your personal information in our custody or control, you may write to the Society’s Executive Director at:
Canadian Hemochromatosis Society
Suite 285 – 7000 Minoru Blvd
Richmond, BC Canada V6Y 3Z5
Toll-Free (Canada): 1-877-BAD-IRON (1-877-223-4766)
Tel: (604) 279-7135
Email: office@toomuchiron.ca
Web: www.toomuchiron.ca
Privacy Statement Changes
This privacy statement is effective as of April 2009 and may be revised from time to time.
Awareness of hemochromatosis is strengthened when you add your voice to ours. Nous sommes plus forts unis.
Join Now | Devenez membre
Latest Tweets / Tweets récent
Cdn Hemochromatosis@IronOutCanada·
8 Jul
The Canadian Hemochromatosis Society is pleased to invite you to our Member Lecture Series on July 14, 2020, featuring Dr. Paul Adams! Register:http://ow.ly/gKGG50AtkGy
Reply on Twitter 1280970628473008128Retweet on Twitter 1280970628473008128Like on Twitter 1280970628473008128Twitter 1280970628473008128
Cdn Hemochromatosis@IronOutCanada·
8 Jul
If you missed Prof. Pierre Brissot’s lecture, you are still able to watch the recorded presentation! http://ow.ly/7FsY50AtkmQ
Reply on Twitter 1280969006153904128Retweet on Twitter 1280969006153904128Like on Twitter 1280969006153904128Twitter 1280969006153904128
Cdn Hemochromatosis@IronOutCanada·
7 Jul
Hey Calgary! We would like to invite you to join us on a Zoom call coffee meet up, taking place on
July 9th at 6:30 pm. Register: http://ow.ly/XPCB50As7n7
Live in a different city? Contact us if you are interested in assistance in organizing a coffee meet up in your area.
Reply on Twitter 1280578084803133440Retweet on Twitter 1280578084803133440Like on Twitter 1280578084803133440Twitter 1280578084803133440
Load More…
Follow us @IronOutCanada Suivez-nous sur @IronOutCanada »
Upcoming Events / Événements à venir
17-Dec-2020 - 17-Dec-2020
Canada-Wide Holiday Meet-Up
All events / Tous les événements »
Featured Sponsor / Commanditaire vedette
All sponsors / Tous les commanditaires »
